Justin White

Web Designer / Developer

1322 Montgomery Drive Charleston, IL (217) 549-6147 kyjus25@gmail.com

SKILLS

I am Microsoft certified in Database Fundamentals, I have created my own CMS in the past that my father uses regularly in his business to this day. I have written custom plugins and modules for Wordpress, Drupal, and Magento. I am a very fast learner and an even harder worker. I enjoy deadlines, but enjoy meeting them even more. I especially enjoy problem-solving, hence why programming is such a perfect niche. I have a variety of knowledge in computer repair, both hardware and software troubleshooting, and very familiar with all Microsoft Office software, as well as basic knowledge of the entire Adobe creative suite. I specialize in all things web (HTML, JS, JQuery, PHP, Node, Angular, Typescript, React, RxJS). I have managed several Digital Ocean VPNs running an Apache web server and use SSH, FTP, and version control regularly.

For a complete and regularly updated resource for my current experience and finished websites up until this point, please refer to my LinkedIn account.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/justin-white-540972123/

EXPERIENCE

Pavlov Media - Software Developer

Aug 2018 - Present

- Create and maintain Single Page Applications in Node.js, Angular, and TypeScript
- Integrate front end with back end using RESTful APIs to communicate with one-another
- Use reactive programming with RxJS to streamline UI/UX design
- Contribute to SCRUM and Agile planning and development processes
- Use version control to collaborate and integrate my sprint tasks with others
- Create custom reusable libraries using a Nexus Repository

Imagine This! Marketing Group - Web Developer

Aug 2016 - Aug 2018

- Create and maintain websites in varying CMS platforms
- Email and database troubleshooting
- Offer senior assistance to our web development team
- Create custom Wordpress plugins to integrate with the needs of our clients

KFC / A&W. Charleston IL - Crew

Apr 2013 - Apr 2016

- My main role is a fry cook, but I also assist with the making and packing for both KFC and A&W as often as I am needed.
- I have also assisted the managers several times with their truck counts, and have been
 offered a managerial position several times throughout my time at KFC, but have declined
 due to conflicts with my past school schedules and/or the commute distance from
 Mattoon.

Site Carpenter Websites, Charleston IL - Freelance - Web Designer

Jan 2014 - Apr 2016

- Designing and implementing Site Carpenter's proprietary CMS into those themes. I have
 designed the websites for many businesses throughout the Charleston surrounding area.
 This includes Pro-Mow Lawn Care, P.A.D.S., Hager Tree Farm, Standing Stone Community
 Center, and several others. All websites can be found at Site Carpenter's website.
- Occasionally, the clients will require components in their website that the CMS does not
 include, or they request components that they have in their Wordpress or Drupal site they
 would like included, so it is my job to design a custom application that suits their needs,
 usually in PHP or Jquery.

Heartland Dental, Effingham IL - Internship - Website Creator / Editor

Jan 2015 - June 2015

- Helped in the converting of all 500+ websites into Drupal "thumbprints".
- When offices needed revisions to their website (doctor changes, bio additions, etc.) it was also my job to correct them.

SuperInterns.com - Internship - Web Developer

Mar 2016 - May 2016

- Developing new Wordpress theme without the use of Visual Composer
- Lead team meetings and organizing group projects

Walmart - Freight Unloader and Stocker (CAP 2)

Apr 2016 - Aug 2016

- Zone aisles
- Unload truck
- Process truck
- Stock shelves

Dimond Bros Insurance - Freelance - Web Developer

May 2016 - Jun 2016

• Develop training web application.

EDUCATION

Lake Land College, Mattoon - IT Programming

2014 - 2016

Earning my Associates Degree for general programming. This course has taught me Java, C#, HTML5, JQuery, Javascript, and PHP with brief AJAX. In addition, the course has included classes on computer hardware, network management, and SQL databases. I was a member of Club IT for 2 years, but decided not to take part this year due to my limited free time to work with.

Charleston High School, Charleston

2010 - 2014

Graduated with High Honors. Took college level courses in Photoshop and Microsoft Office.